（信(しん)）ハァ… ハァ…
ハァ… ハァ…
（信）ああ くそ！ もう３日だぞ
Geez! It's been three days already!
いつになったら 戻れるんだよ？
まったく！
When're we gonna get home, dammit?!
（漂(ひょう)）ムダにしゃべるな 信
疲れるだけだ
Don't waste your energy talking, Xin.
It'll just tire you out.
だけどよ…
But...!
We'll reach the village in another three days.
（漂）あと３日も歩けば村に着く
いい鍛錬だと思おうぜ
Let's think of it as training.
（信）普通なら
馬車で運ぶ荷物と道のりだろう
You'd normally go by horse-drawn carriage for bags this heavy and a distance this far!
俺たち下僕は馬以下かよ？
Are us servants lower than horses?
（漂）だからさ　だから鍛錬して
下僕から抜け出すのさ
I told you, think of it as training for when we break free from being servants.
I know.
分かってらぁ
I get it, but...
分かってっけどよ…
What's this sound?
（漂）地響きか？
An earth tremor?
No! It's coming from over there!
違う！ あっちのほうからだ！
（漂）だな！
Yeah!
( Flag - Qin )
( Flag - Zhao )
War.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）戦…
今 目の前で
繰り広げられているのは―
What was unfolding before their eyes
２人の少年が
初めて目にする本物の戦だった
was the first real war the two boys had ever seen.
とはいえ それは―
However, it was nothing more than skirmish between two neighboring feudal states near their borders.
隣国との国境付近で起きた
小競り合いにすぎなかった
だが ２人の少年は そこに―
But those two boys saw the future of their lives in it.
自分たちの生きる未来を
はっきりと見た
"This is the place we belong." They thought.
“俺たちの生きる場所は
ここだ”と
Piao! Is this a real war?!
（信）漂！ これが本物の戦か！
（漂）ああ！ 信…
俺たちは あの中で英雄になろうぜ
Yeah! Xin, we'll become heroes in there!
古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望が解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars lasting a monumentally long 500 years erupted all across China.
激烈なる戦争と戦乱の嵐が―
500年という
途方もなく長きにわたって―
中国全土に吹き荒れていた
欲望 快楽 苦痛 恐怖…
Desire, pleasure, pain, fear.
With that world filled with such relentless despair, it was as though a dragon had invaded.
過酷で絶望に満ちた その世界には
竜がいたに違いない
“時代”という名の竜が
A dragon called the "era".
And like the burning flames of a dragon,
そして
竜の炎に焼かれるかのように―
100を超える国は次々と滅び
今や ７国に淘汰(とうた)されていた
over one hundred states were destroyed one by one until only seven were left standing.
Yan, Qi, Zhao, Wei, Han, Chu...
燕(えん) 斉(せい) 趙(ちょう) 魏(ぎ) 韓(かん) 楚(そ)…
そして 秦(しん)である
and Qin.
７つの大国は おのおのが
おのおのを食らい尽くすように―
The seven great powers, in order to devour each other,
took up their swords of desire and continuously pierced the throats of enemy states.
欲望の剣を 敵国の喉元に向かって
突き立て続けた
( Flag - Yan )
( Flag - Qi )
The world knew it as the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
世にいう春秋戦国時代である
( Flag - Zhao )
( Flag - Wei )
( Flag - Han )
そして今 西の果て 秦の国から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the state of Qin in the far West.
( Flag - Chu )
大きな歴史の風が
吹き荒れようとしている
( Flag - Qin )
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king that ran the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を走り抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
KoolKidsK
Hugh_Jasss
Yoshu-sama
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
Kewl0210
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hosonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
FZeroWing
prefix-
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Nameless Boy
Watch it!
危ねえ！
（漂）まだまだ！
Not yet!
（漂）おおっと！
（信）
ンンッ！ まだまだ！ おらー！
（信）漂 こっちだ！
（漂）おう！
Over here, Piao!
（信）この野郎！ まだまだ！
You bastard!
Not yet!
（漂）オッ… ウワッ！
馬鹿力(ばかぢから)め！
You damn strong bastard!
ヤーッ！
（漂）こっち？
Here?
Hey!
（漂）ほい！
（殴る音）
しゃー！ これで
333勝 332敗 587引き分けだな
All right! That gives me 333 wins, 332 loses, and 587 draws!
１つ勝ち越しっと
I'm one win up on you!
Dammit! One more round!
くそ！ もう１本だ もう１本！
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）うん？
You're open!
隙あり！
（漂）待て　誰か来る
Wait!
Someone's coming.
Huh? I got a hit in?
（漂）ありゃ？ 入った？
なに見てんだよ？ おっさん ああ？
（漂）ああっ！
What're you lookin' at, old man?!
Huh?
Moron, moron, moron, moron!
よく見ろ！
あのいでたちに あの馬車
Look closely!
Those clothes and that carriage!
This guy's clearly from a pretty high-status family!
（漂）
かなり位の高い士族に違いないぞ
Like that matters!
関係ねえだろう！
（漂）ある！ ぶっ殺されるぞ
It does! You could be killed.
What's going on with you two?
なんじゃ お前ら
ケンカしていたわりには
仲がいいな
You were fighting, but you seem to be getting along relatively well.
That wasn't a fight, it was a match!
（信）ケンカじゃねえ 試合だ！
おっさんのせいで
負けちまったじゃねえか
And because of you, I lost, old man!
“おっさん”？
（信）これで 1,253戦やって―
Old man?
This was our 1,253rd match, and now I have 332 wins, 334 losses, and 587 ties!
俺の332勝 334敗 587引き分け
２つ差がついたのは
１年ぶりだ こんちくしょう！
It's the first time in a year there's been a difference of two between us, goddammit!
1,253rd?
1,253？
ハハハハッ…
何を言いだすかと思えば
What a statement. I guess you are just kids after all.
所詮は子供　なかなか
あっぱれな大ボラを吹きおる
That's quite some exaggerating you're doing there.
Have you really had fierce battles like that over one thousand times?
あんな激しい試合を 本当に
1,000を超えて続けてきたのか？
まるで正気の沙汰じゃない
It seems completely insane.
ハハハッ…
驚かれるのも ごムリありません
I don't blame you for being surprised.
あなたのような方には
理解できないでしょうが
I wouldn't expect someone of your stature to understand,
but we're orphans.
俺たちは孤児です
He and I lost our parents in a war, and became slaves.
（信）こいつも 俺も
戦争で家族を亡くして奴隷になり
Now we've been picked up as servants!
今は拾われて 下僕の身だ
Of course, our parents didn't leave us anything.
（漂）当然
親から残された財産なんかない
あるとすれば この頑丈な体だけ
Just these strong bodies.
だけど それで十分だ！
But that's plenty!
そう！ 剣さえ振れる体があれば
俺も信も十分なんです
Yes! As long as we can swing a sword, both Xin and I are satisfied!
For everything we lost from fighting, we'll take back with fighting!
（信）
戦いで全てを奪われちまった分―
俺たちも戦いで奪い取る！
（漂）そのとおり！
That's right!
As soon as we can, we'll enter a war and raise our military standing!
（信）俺たちは
とっとと戦に出て 武功を挙げる！
（漂）２人で鍛えた力と技で
手柄を勝ち取る！
With the strength and technique we've developed together,
we'll gain great achievements!
We'll make our way up from rock bottom and build our own house!
（信）どん底から成り上がって
自分の家を建てる！
A luxurious mansion with a huge garden, a huge gate!
（漂）でっかい庭と でっかい門の
豪華な屋敷だ！
We'll take some nice girls as brides,
（信）
いいとこの きれいな ねえちゃんを
嫁さんにして たくさんガキを作り
have lots of kids, and hire more servants than you can count!
数え切れねえほどの
召し使いを抱える！
（２人）そして…
And...
Our names will echo all across China!
２人の名を中華全土に響き渡らせ…
We'll be the most powerful generals under the heavens!
俺たちは
天下最強の大将軍になるんだ！
Laughing again, bastard?!
また大笑いしやがって…
ぶっ殺す！
I'll kill you!
This meeting may bring about what's needed to tear apart the dark clouds that hang over the State of Qin.
（昌文君）この出会い…
我が秦国の暗雲を切り裂く出会いに
なるやもしれぬ
State of Qin   Xianyang
（ナレーター）
秦国の都 咸陽(かんよう)
The capital of the State of Qin, Xianyang.
The flames of desire whirl everywhere inside that palace.
その王宮の内部では 至る所で
欲望の業火が激しく渦巻いていた
大臣の最高官位である
右丞相(うじょうしょう)の座に就き―
Taking the seat of the highest cabinet minister, Right Chancellor,
若き王を補佐する呂不韋(りょふい)
is the young king's aid, Lü Buwei.
そして
２番手である左丞相(さじょうしょう)となった竭氏(けつし)
And his second in command, the Left Chancellor, Jie Shi.
Right
Minister
Lü
Buwei
Jie
Shi
Left
Minister
The Imperial Court was split in two, revolving around these two men.
この両者を軸に
朝廷は真っ二つに割れていた
その対立は激化の一途をたどり
That antagonism reached a point of intensity
日夜
血で血を洗う抗争が続いていた
where a dispute with blood being washed with blood continued day and night.
And now,
そして今…
with his eye on the throne, the younger brother of the king, Chengjiao, has allied himself with Jie Shi.
玉座を狙う王の弟 成蟜(せいきょう)が
竭氏と結び付き
The inside of the royal palace was in a state of near upheaval.
王宮内は風雲急を告げていた
（里典(りてん)）オエッ… 水 水！
（せきこみ）
This's terrible!
（里典の妻）こりゃ何だい？
What the hell is this?!
（里典）
とても食えたもんじゃないぞ！
This is totally inedible!
（有(ゆう)）まずい まずい まずい！
Yucky, yucky, yucky!
（里典）どっちが作ったんだ？
Which one of you guys made this?
Of course, Xin!
やっぱり信か！
（有）お前だと思ってたよ ンッ…
I thought it was you!
漂と違って
ホントにダメなヤツだな お前は
Unlike Piao, you really are useless.
料理もダメ 掃除もダメ
You're no good at cooking and you're no good cleaning!
“役立たず”っていうんだよ
お前みたいなの
Somebody like you serves no purpose at all!
ウワッ！ にらんだ！
おっ父！ 信が おいらをにらんだよ
He glared at me!
Dad! Xin glared at me!
（里典）なに？
What?!
Who do you think you are?!
お前というヤツは！
（ムチの音）
Who're you glaring at?!
なに にらんでんだ お前は！
文句あるとでもいうのか
Have you got a problem or something?!
こんなヤツ要らないよ
漂と違って 何にもできないじゃん
We don't need a guy like this!
He can't do anything like Piao can!
（里典）誰のおかげで
生きていられると思ってんだ？
Who do you think you have to thank for being alive right now?!
戦争孤児のお前らを
この村の村長であるわしが―
You're alive because I, the mayor of this village, went out of his way
to take you two war orphans in and raise you!
わざわざ
養ってやってるからだろうが！
（信）くっそー！
Shiiiit!
Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit! Shit!
くそ！ くそ！ くそ！ くそ！
（床を殴る音）
（漂）聞かれるぞ バカ
お前の声は響くんだ
They'll hear you, you idiot!
Your voice is echoing!
ンッ！
かまうもんか！ もう限界だ！
Ya think I care?!
I can't take it anymore!
あいつら みんな ぶん殴って
こんな家 出てやる！
I'm gonna beat the crap outta those guys and leave this house!
まだ早い
It's too soon for that.
Do you think we have what it takes to earn a living for two people?
（漂）２人だけで食っていけるほど
俺たちに生活力があるか？
飢え死にするだけだ
We'd just starve to death.
Then we'll become thieves or something!
（信）じゃ 盗賊にでもなるさ
この家を真っ先に狙ってやる！
Our first target'll be this house!
（漂）信！
（信）何だよ？
Xin!
What?
（漂）
そんなもんになるために 今まで
鍛えてきたんじゃないだろうが
We haven't been training this whole time in order to become something like that, right?
バカか お前
Are you an idiot?
分かってるよ　冗談だろう 冗談
I get it.
I was just kidding, really.
なんだ てめえ！ まだ何か…
What is it, you?! You've still got a bone to pick with-
（有）すぐ来い 漂！ 早く！
急げ！ えらいことになったんだ
Come right now, Piao! Hurry!
C'mon! Something really big is happening!
これって…
（漂）昼間の…
This is...
The one from this afternoon...
（里典）漂くん！ 漂くん！
（信）“漂くん”？
Piao-kun! Piao-kun!
Piao-kun?
さあさあ 漂くん 急いで急いで
Come now, Piao-kun. Hurry, hurry!
Hey, what about me?
おい 俺は？
（里典）お前は納屋で仕事してろ
You, go do work in the shed!
Piao-kun, this man is called Changwenjun-sama.
漂よ このお方は
昌文君さまとおっしゃって
A very powerful nobleman of the State of Qin.
秦国内にて 有力な貴人であり
王宮に はべる大臣の
おひとりであられる
And one of the ministers that serves in the royal palace.
“王宮に はべる”…
Serves in the royal palace!
A minister?
“大臣”？
Piao, today this man will be paying for your freedom.
漂… 今日をもって お前は―
このお方に
お身請けされることとなった
なん …だって？
What... did he say?
Piao! Starting tomorrow, you will be working at the royal palace!
漂よ 明日より
お前は王宮で働いてもらう
（漂）私が王宮で？
（昌文君）そうだ
Me, at the royal palace?
Yes.
（漂）あ… あの…
よく意味が分からないのですが
U-Um... I'm not sure I understand.
王宮内のことは ここでは話せぬが
I cannot discuss palace matters with you here,
任を受けて
極めて重要な職務に就いてもらう
but should you accept it, you will be taking a duty of the utmost importance.
B-But I...
で… では 私が…
Are you saying I can be a government officer?
私が仕官できるということですか？
（昌文君）さよう
That is correct.
お… 王宮で仕官？
すげえ すげえ！
Government officer?
Awesome! That's awesome!
（漂）信は？ あの… 信も一緒に！
信は私と同等の力があります
And Xin? Um, let Xin come with me!
Xin is as strong as I am!
No!
否！
No! I will only bring one person with me!
わしが連れていくのは ただひとり
漂！ お前だけだ！
Only you, Piao!
どうした？ 漂
早くお引き受けせぬか！
What's wrong, Piao?
Hurry, you must accept!
I'm sorry. Could I please have one more day to make my decision?
（漂）すみません
どうか１日のご猶予をくださいませ
I think I'd like to sort out my feelings.
気持ちを整理したく思います
（里典）アア… お前 何を…
What are you...?
I understand. I will return tomorrow.
分かった　また明日まいる
信！
Xin!
信…
Xin...
Xin, where are you? Xin!
信 どこだ？ 信！
なんで
すぐ引き受けなかったんだ？
Why didn't you accept right then and there?
田舎村の下僕が
いきなり王宮で仕官なんて
A servant in a country village suddenly being a military officer in the royal palace?!
夢でも ありえねえ話じゃねえか！
Stories like that don't even happen in dreams!
I barely understand what's happening myself, but...
（漂）何が どうなってるのか
さっぱり分からないが…
I've been training in order to raise myself up step by step on my own power.
俺は 自分の力で―
１歩１歩のし上がっていくために
これまで鍛えてきた
こんな裏道使うために お前と―
I didn't work hard with you every day in order to take a shortcut like this.
切磋琢磨(せっさたくま)してきたわけじゃない
（信）バカ…
You idi-
Do you think I'd really say that, Xin?
…なんて言わないぜ 信
俺は行くぞ
I'm... going!
当然だ！
Of course you are!
やっぱり強いな お前
（信）当たり前(めえ)だろう！
You really are strong, you know!
Course I am, dammit!
これなら すぐに会える
（信）えっ？
I'm sure I'll see you again soon!
Hurry and catch up with me!
とっとと追いついてこいよ
２人の行き着く所は同じだぞ
We're headed to the same place!
Right! I'll overtake you before you know what happened!
分かってらぁ
あっという間に追い抜いてやるぜ！
（信）ハアッ！
Welcome!
（露天商）いらっしゃい！
（露天商）見てってちょうだいよ
Come look!
Need any goat milk?!
（露天商）ヤギの乳は要らんか？
Xin! Your tip!
（露天商）信！ 駄賃だ
Thanks.
も～らい！
（露天商）はい ご苦労さん
Okay, good work.
By the way, it's been about a month since Piao went to the capital, right?
そういや 漂が都へ行ってから
ひと月くらいか
信 お前 少し変わったな
（信）そうか？
Xin, you've changed a little, haven't you?
Really?
ああ　赤ちゃんザルが
子ザルになったって感じだ
Yeah. Like a baby monkey turning into a child monkey.
What'd you say, dammit?!
なんだと？ こら！
ハハハッ… いいかげん慣れたか？
Looks like you've gotten used to it.
（露天商）
漂のヤツは どうしてるかなぁ
I wonder how Piao's doing...
下僕に
宮仕えが務まるわけねえもんなぁ
You wouldn't think a servant would be fit for working in a palace, would ya?
バカ野郎！ 漂なら
王宮だろうが どこだろうが…
You moron! Royal palace or whatever, Piao could make it in a...!
They locked me out of the royal palace.
（商人Ｂ）王宮から
締め出し食らったんじゃ―
どこに
商品 売りつけりゃいいんだよ？
Where am I supposed to sell my merchandise?!
たまったもんじゃねえや
（信）うん？
I don't have enough savings for this!
（商人Ａ）俺もだ　どうも王宮内は
商売どころじゃないって話だな
Me, too. Anyhow, it looks like we just won't be able to do business in the royal palace.
（商人Ｂ）おい… じゃ
あのウワサ 本当かもしれないな
Hey, then that rumor could be true.
（商人Ａ）
あれか　王宮内で反乱が起きて―
That one? The one about there being a rebellion in the palace?
大王さまは
家来ともども皆殺しってやつ
And the king even killing all of his retainers?
You've heard it, too? Damn that rumor's spreading fast...
（商人Ｂ）
ありゃ？ お前さんも知ってんの？
ウワサが広がるのは早いねえ
What?
なんだって？
（露天商）心配すんな 信
Don't worry about it, Xin.
There are always rumors like that. Don't worry about it.
そんなウワサ しょっちゅうだ
気にすんな
R-Right.
（竭氏）なんだと？
確かなのだな？
What?
Left Chancellor    Jie Shi
You are certain of this?
（伝令）はっ！
魏国遠征中の呂不韋のもとに―
Yes, my lord.
There were no discrepancies in the report. A horse was seen hastily heading toward Lü Buwei on his campaign in Wei.
早馬が向かったとの報告に
相違ありません
追っ手は？ 当然
追っ手は放ったのであろうな？
Follow them!
You of course sent a pursuer after them, didn't you?
（伝令）
はっ！ そ… それは もちろん
Y-Yes! Of course we did!
（竭氏）我々の決起を知った
呂不韋のヤツめが―
That bastard Lü Buwei knows about our uprising.
大王側に加担したら どうなるか…
Do you know what will happen if he supports the king's side?
Not only will we never capture the royal throne, but this kingdom will split in two!
王の座を奪うどころか
国が真っ二つに壊れてしまうわ
こうなれば 猶予はない
一刻も早く事を起こせるよう―
We can postpone it no longer!
Report to all units that we are to act immediately!
各部隊に伝えるのだ
（伝令）御意！
Understood!
（成蟜）落ち着け　暑苦しい
Calm down. It's stifling.
（成蟜）
それも考えのうちに
あっての計画であろう
That is within the scope of our plan as well.
King's Younger Brother Chenjiao
Don't start causing an uproar now.
今更 騒ぎ立てるな
（竭氏）ははっ！ 御意
Ah, understood.
（成蟜）だが 事を急ぐこと自体は
なかなか面白い
But the idea about speeding things up is actually quite interesting.
俺としては
兄上の首を早く見たいものでなぁ
I'd like to see Big Brother's severed head as soon as possible.
（竭氏）ははっ！ お任せください
Sir, just leave it to me.
（竭氏）皆の者 時は来た！
（家臣たち）オーッ！
Everyone, the time has come!
This man is called Changwenjun-sama.
（里典）このお方は
昌文君さまとおっしゃって
秦国内にて 有力な貴人であり
A very powerful nobleman of the State of Qin.
王宮に はべる大臣の
おひとりであられる
And one of the ministers that serves in the royal palace.
I cannot discuss palace matters with you here,
（昌文君）
王宮内のことは ここでは話せぬが
任を受けて
重要な職務に就いてもらう
but should you accept it, you will be taking a duty of the utmost importance.
（商人Ａ）
あれか　王宮内で反乱が起きて―
That one? The one about there being a rebellion in the palace?
And the king even killing all of his retainers?
大王さまは
家来ともども皆殺しってやつ
（信）漂… 大丈夫だよな？ お前は
Piao, you're okay, right...?
Piao. This is Xin. Starting today, you'll be living with him.
（里典）漂！
今日から お前と一緒に住む信だ
He's an orphan like you. Teach him your job.
お前と同じ孤児だ
仕事を教えてやれ
So your name's Piao?
（信）
お前 漂っていうのか？ よろしくな
Nice to meet you!
Xin, would you like to have a sword match with me?
（漂）信 俺と剣の試合しないか？
（信）えっ？
面白(おもしれ)え！ やるやる！
Sounds interesting!
Sure, I'll do it!
You may have thought "I'm lucky someone picked me up", but that's naive.
（漂）お前 運よく拾われたなんて
思ってるかもしれないけど 甘いぜ
In the end, both you and I are servants to that man Li Dian's house.
結局
俺も お前も あの里典の家の下僕だ
（信）何が言いてえんだ？
What're you trying to say?
Even if a servant becomes an adult, he's still a servant.
（漂）
下僕は 大人になっても下僕だ
Then he marries some servant woman and his children become servants, too.
どっかの下僕の女と結婚して
その子供も やっぱり下僕になる
俺は そんなのはイヤだ
I don't want that!
（信）俺だってイヤだ
でも どうなるもんでもないだろう
Well neither do I!
But there's nothing we can do, is there?
（漂）抜け出すんだ 剣の力で
We can escape it! With the power of the sword!
Power of the sword?
（信）剣の力？
（漂）戦に出るんだ
We'll join a war!
If we get military achievements recognized in a war,
戦で武功を挙げて 認められれば
下僕から抜け出せる
we can escape being servants!
You're amazing, Piao!
（信）漂！ お前 すごいな！
（信）オリャ！
We have swords!
俺たちには剣がある
剣があるんだよ！
We have our swords!
漂…
お前 今 何してるんだ？
Piao, what're you doing right now?
俺 絶対 追いつくから…
ちゃんと待ってろよ
I'm definitely gonna catch up to you,
so you'd better wait for me!
ただいま… 信…
I'm home... Xin...
（信）漂ーっ！
Piao!
漂！
Hold on, Piao!
しっかりしろ 漂！ 目を開けろ！
目を開けるんだ！
Open your eyes!
Open your eyes, dammit!
Wh-What's going on, Xin?
な… 何事だ？ 信　盗っ人(と)か？
Thieves?
里典 医者を！ 早く！
医者を早く！
Li Dian! A doctor! Hurry!
Go get a doctor!
（有）
ひょ… 漂！ 何なんだ？ この血は
P-Piao!
Wh-What's all this blood?!
Just go get a doctor!
いいから 医者だ！
Xin...
（漂）信…
It doesn't hurt.
痛みがない
（漂）医者は… もういい
I don't... need a doctor.
漂 何なんだよ？ 都で 一体 何が…
Piao, what's going on?
What the the hell happened at the capital?
I got caught up in... the king's younger brother's... rebellion...
（漂）王弟の反乱に巻き込まれた
（信）王弟？
The king's little brother?
お… 王の弟君が反乱を？
一体 どういうことだ！
Th... The king's little brother started a rebellion?
What're you talking about?!
あれか　王宮内で反乱が起きて―
The one about there being a rebellion in the palace?
大王さまは
家来ともども皆殺しってやつ
And the king even killing all of his retainers?
（漂）王の側は…
あの昌文君と僅かな兵力のみ
The only ones at the king's side...
are that man Changwenjun and a few soldiers...
王弟の勢力は…
The king's younger brother's forces were... large enough to... overthrow the capital...
都を転覆させるほど
大きく… 強く…
They were strong... and implacable...
また 執念深い…
（信）あまり しゃべるな
Don't talk so much.
They'll follow the blood... The pursuer they sent will be here any second...
血をたどって ここへも
まもなく追っ手が来るだろう
Wh-What?
な… なに？
（信）追っ手…
Pursuer...
Li Dian... When that happens...
（漂）里典… そのときは―
tell them that someone you didn't know just broke into your shed and died...
見知らぬ人間が
勝手に納屋で死んだということに
どうか 亡骸(なきがら)は されるがままに
（里典）ああ…
Please, just leave the corpse as it is...
I-I under-
触らせねえし！
I won't let them touch you!
１人も生かしちゃ帰さねえ
１人もだ！
I won't let one of them go back alive!
Not a single one!
アア…
その威勢が聞けて うれしいよ 信
Ah... I'm delighted to hear that vigor, Xin.
（信）もう しゃべるな
Don't... talk any more.
（漂）いや…
お前に頼みたいことがある
No.
I have a favor I need to ask you.
（紙を広げる音）
（信）地図？
A map?
It's a map to a village west of here called Heibei Village.
（漂）ここより西にある―
黒卑村(こくひむら)という村の地図だ
（里典）ハッ…
（里典）黒卑村…
Heibei Village... That's a place where thieves and murderers from all across the kingdom gather. A village of outlaws.
物取りや人殺しが
全土から流れてくる無法者たちの村
普通の人間なら
まず生きて帰れぬと言われる―
That's that terrible place they say no normal person ever leaves from alive!
恐ろしい場所ではないか
Xin... I came here to give this to you.
信… これをお前に渡しに来たんだ
今すぐ そこに行ってくれ
Go there, right away!
な… 何なんだ？
一体 どういうこと？
Wh-What're you talking about? You want me to...
I don't understand at all!
さっぱり ワケが分かんねえ！
（漂）いいな？ 信
Do you hear me, Xin?!
託したぞ！
I'm entrusting this to you!
Got it...
（信）分かった…
I've got it, Piao.
分かった 漂… 分かったから…
I understand, so...
死ぬんじゃねえよ 漂… こんな…
So don't die, Piao!
Not like this...
お前… ２人で…
You... and I...
were supposed to become the greatest generals in the world, weren't we?!
２人で天下の大将軍に
なるっつったじゃねえかよ！
（漂）なるさ…
We will...
信… 俺たちは 力も心も等しい
Xin... Our strength and our hearts are alike...
We're one in body and soul...
２人は一心同体だ
お前が羽ばたけば…
If you flap your wings...
I'll be... there with you, too...
俺も そこにいる
信… 俺を天下に連れていってくれ
Xin... take me... with you across the world...
Piao!
漂ーっ！
Piao... Piao...
（信）漂… 漂…
なんでだよ！
Why?
Why did this happen?!
なんでだよ！
（壁を殴る音）
S-Stop, Xin!
（里典）よ… よせ 信！
皆殺しだ！ よくも漂を！
ただじゃ殺さねえぞ！
I'll kill them all! How could they do this to Piao?!
And I won't just kill them!
漂の敵(かたき)！ 八つ裂きに １人残らず！
（頭を打ちつける音）
I'll avenge Piao!
I'll tear them limb from limb!
I won't leave a single one left!
I'll kill them all! I'll kill them all!
皆殺しだ！ 皆殺しだ！
All of them... I'll kill all of them!
皆殺し… 皆殺しだ！ アア…
皆殺しだ！ 皆殺しだ！
All of them! All of them! All of them!
（信）皆殺し！ 皆殺し！
All of them! All of them!
おい…
Hey!
All of them! I'll kill all of them!
皆殺し！ 皆殺しだ！
（有）信！
（殴る音）
Xin!
漂の死をムダにするなよ 信！
Don't let Piao's death be for nothing,
Xin!
なんだと？ このクソガキ
（有）おいら…
What was that, you shitty brat?!
I...
お前のことは嫌いだったけど
漂のことは大好きだったんだ
I hated you, but...
I really liked Piao!
だから
おいらも漂の敵を討ってやりたい
So I want to get revenge for Piao, too!
I want to chop the person who did this to Piao to pieces!
漂をこんな目に遭わせたヤツを
切り刻んでやりたい！
だけど 信は行かなきゃ
But... you have to go, Xin!
何が起こってるか
おいらには分からないけど
I don't know what'll happen, but...
信は 絶対 ここに…
You definitely have to go here.
漂の死をムダにしないために―
So Piao's death doesn't go to waste,
信は
ここに行かなきゃいけないんだ！
you have to go here, Xin!
（漂）これをお前に渡しに来たんだ
I came here to give this to you.
今すぐ そこに行ってくれ
いいな？ 信
Go there, right away!
Do you hear me, Xin?
託したぞ！
I'm entrusting this to you!
（里典）行くつもりか？ 信
You really intend to go, Xin?
Don't do it!
やめておけ　黒卑村は人殺しの村だ
ひと度 足を踏み入れれば―
Heibei Village is a town of murderers!
They say that if you set foot in there,
you'll never come back alive! It's a horrifying place!
生きては帰れぬといわれる
恐ろしい場所だ
And we don't know what's going on with the king's younger brother's rebellion...
それに 王弟さまの反乱とは 一体…
（信）そんなもん 関係ねえ
None of that matters.
人殺しの巣窟だろうが
何が起こっていようが関係ねえ
It doesn't matter if it's a den of murderers, and it doesn't matter what's going on!
漂は 俺に“行け”っつった
Piao told me to go.
So...
だから…
So... So I'm going!
だから 行くだけだ！
Jie Shi.
（成蟜）竭氏
（竭氏）はっ！
My lord?
お前は この国を
手にすることに必死だろうが
I know that you are desperate to gain control of this country, but...
俺は そんなものに興味はない
I'm not interested in things like that.
I just want to see proof of my big brother's bloodstained death.
俺は ただ
あの兄が薄汚れた血に染まり
絶命した証しが見たいだけだ
（竭氏）
はっ！ すぐご覧になれます
Yes, my lord. You will see that soon.
フン… どうせ その袖の内側で
あざ笑っているのだろう？
But anyhow, you're sneering behind those sleeves of yours, aren't you?
所詮 俺も兄も あの成り上がりの
呂不韋あってこその―
After all, my brother and I are in the positions we're in because of that upstart Lü Buwei.
この地位であると
（竭氏）何をおっしゃいます
What is this you speak of?
That blessing is because of the enthronement of your father King Zhuangxiang.
父君 荘襄王(そうじょうおう)の即位は
その徳のなせるところ
呂不韋の力で玉座を得たなどという
根も葉もなきウワサ…
The idea that the throne was gained because of Lü Buwei is an entirely baseless rumor...
ここまで来て 猿芝居はよせ
Would you please stop the monkey show at this point?
I joined hands with you for the very reason of severing that unsavory chain.
俺は その忌まわしき鎖をも
断ち切りたいからこそ―
お前と手を組んだのだ
（成蟜）敦(とん) 前へ
（敦）はっ！
Dun, forward.
Sir!
（成蟜）
この男は 貧しい職人の家の出でな
This man came from the family of a poor worker.
He was thrown out by his parent, but he has talent with the sword and the writing brush.
親に捨てられたが
剣と筆の才があり
And here at Xianyang, he finally rose to the position of serving me.
この咸陽で ついに
俺に はべるまで のし上がった
Now he owns a mansion and even sends an allowance to the parent that abandoned him.
今では 屋敷を持ち―
自分を捨てた親に
仕送りをするほどだ
（供）ほう…
呂不韋までとは いかぬが
底辺から這(は)い上がった者
I can't say he's risen as much as Lü Buwei,
but he's someone who rose up from the base of society.
I can't stand
（成蟜）
我慢ならんのだ… そういう連中が
people like that.
いくら高貴な衣服で身を包もうと
中身は変えられん！
No matter how much you dress someone up as a noble, the person they are inside does not change!
それは 兄とて同じこと
It's the same for my older brother!
あいつの母親は―
His mother was a lowborn woman without any connection to the royal family!
王家と何のゆかりもない
卑しい身分の女だ
For someone like that to leave me where I am and take the throne...
そんなヤツが この俺を差し置いて
玉座に就くなど… 許されん！
is unforgivable!
I, who have a mother of a royal family, am the one fit to be king!
王族の母を持つ俺こそが
王に ふさわしいのだ！
（成蟜）
玉座を兄に奪われて 俺は知った
I knew my throne would be stolen from me by my older brother.
As well as the opposition the people of the palace had towards me deep down...
宮殿の者たちの
俺たちに対する本心を
結局は皆 王という地位に
ひざまずいているだけなのだ
In the end, everyone just kneels to the position of king.
Every last one of them amount to nothing more than that.
どいつも こいつも
所詮 その程度のヤツらだ
だから 俺は人を信じない
But I don't trust in people.
（成蟜）信じられるのは権力欲
全ての人間の醜い欲望だけだ
What I do trust in is the desire for power.
Just the ugly desires of all humans.
Using that, I carry out things according to my wishes.
俺は それを利用して
思いどおりに事を運ぶ
Driving Lü Buwei into a campaign was just one example.
呂不韋を遠征に追い出したのも
そのひとつだ
（竭氏）
しかし 呂不韋は侮れません
But you must not make light of Lü Buwei.
We should assemble a few hundred thousand soldiers to prepare for the unlikely.
万が一のときは
数十万の兵を挙げねばなりますまい
玉璽(ぎょくじ)が必要だというのだろう？
あんなものは ただの印にすぎん
Are you saying you need the sovereign's seal ?
That thing is nothing but a mere symbol.
Find a way to do it with your own hands.
お前の手で どうとでもしておけ
（竭氏）ははっ！
Y-Yes my lord.
Soon it will return to how it was five years ago.
もうすぐ５年前に戻れる
The way things should be.
５年前のあるべき姿にな
（王騎(おうき)）ウフッ…
（王騎）昌文君は どうしました？
What of Changwenjun?
Sir! It has gone just as you expected.
（騰(とう)）はっ！ 殿の思惑どおりに
（王騎）フフフフッ…
It looks to be interesting.
（王騎）面白くなりそうですねえ
Hey, why don't you do something?
（有）
ねえ どうして何もしないの？
You can't just leave him here!
このままじゃ あんまりだよ
漂が かわいそうだよ！
I feel really bad for Piao!
Well...
漂は“追っ手が来る”
Piao said "A pursuer is coming. Don't do anything to the corpse."
“亡骸には何もするな”と
言っていた　それは 一体…
What could he have meant by...
（妻）ヒイッ！
（徐完(じょかん)）嬴政(えいせい)…
Ying Zheng.
（徐完）
貴様ら こいつと話したか？
Did you bastards talk to him?
い… いえ
物音がしたので出てきたら…
N-No! We just heard a noise, and when we came outside
t-this person was... a-already dead...!
こ… この人が…
す… 既に息はなく…
（徐完）そうか　命拾いしたな
I see. So, you managed to just barely escape with your life?
Stop!
（有）やめろ！
（徐完）うん？
（徐完）
おい　こいつの剣は どうした？
Hey. What happened to his sword?
（里典）
し… 知りません！ わしらは何も…
I-I don't know!
We don't know anything...!
何か隠しているな？
You're hiding something.
（里典）い… いいえ！
わしらは本当に何も…
No!
We really don't know any-
お父！ アッ… ウウ…
Dad!
Hurry up and speak.
早く言え
次は心臓を刺す
The next place I stab will be his heart!
（村人Ａ）おい ホントに来たぜ
Hey, he really showed up.
（村人Ｂ）
こんな時間に こんな所に来るたぁ
Coming to a place like this this late at night?
脳みそねえな このガキ
（村人Ｃ）ハハハッ…
Don't you have any brains, kid?
He's got a wooden sword on his hip, but the sword on his back looks pretty good.
腰のは木剣だが
背中の剣は かなりよさげだねえ
（村人Ｂ）
お前にしちゃ 上出来だ 貂(てん)
You did a good job, Diao. Here.
ほらよ
（銭の音）
（信）おい
（村人Ｂ）うん？
Hey!
ひょっとして
もう ここは黒卑村か？
Would this happen to be Heibei Village?
ハハハッ…
今ごろ気づいても 遅いっつうの
You just noticed that? Man, you're slow!
おとなしく背中の剣を渡しゃ
無傷のまま人買いに売っ払ってやる
Be a good boy and hand over that sword on your back
and we'll sell you to a slave trader without hurting you.
だが 抵抗すりゃ 死体で川泳ぎだ
But if you struggle, you'll end up as a corpse floating down the river.
Which one do you-
どっちが…
（信）悪いな　急いでる
Sorry. I'm in a hurry.
（村人Ｂ）クソガキが！
Shitty brat!
貂！ 村の連中を呼び集めて
あいつを狙わせろ！
Diao! Go call together the people in the village and tell them to go after that guy!
あのクソガキ！
絶対に生かして帰すんじゃねえ！
That shitty brat!
There's no way in hell he's getting home alive!
（村人Ｅ）やられただと？
They got beat?
（村人Ｆ）
ガキが１人じゃなかったのか？
Wasn't there only one kid?!
（村人Ｄ）バカな！
（村人Ｇ）来たぞ！
No way!
He's coming!
（村人Ｇ）あいつだ！
（村人Ｈ）殺せ！
It's him, kill him!
（村人たち）ウワッ！
（村人Ｆ）なんてガキだ…
That's one tough kid!
（村人Ｇ）みんな呼んでこい！
囲んで 逃がすな！
Call everyone! Surround him, don't let him get away!
（村人）メチャ速(はえ)え！
He's freakin' fast!
Hey! Catch him! If we stop him...
おい 捕まえろ！ 捕まえちまえば…
（村人たち）ウワッ！
He's ridiculously strong!
なんちゅう怪力…
（村人Ｇ）バケモノか？ こいつは
Is this guy a monster?!
当たり前だ
Of course...
お前らみたいな
ハンパなヤツらの剣とは違うんだ！
My sword is on different level from you half-hearted bastards!
信！
（信）ああ？
Xin!
Someday, we'll definitely become generals!
俺たちも いつか絶対 将軍になるぞ
はぁ？ なに寝ぼけてんだよ？
…んなもん なれるわけねえだろう
What are you, half asleep?
There's no way we could become something like that.
なれる！ 勝ちまくって…
We will! We'll just keep winning and winning!
手柄を上げて 認められて
上り詰めれば 将軍になれるんだ！
We'll build up achievements!
We'll be recognized!
And if we make it to the top, we'll become generals!
Generals...?
将軍…
そうだ！ 黄金の甲冑(かっちゅう)をまとって
大地を駆け巡り…
That's right! We'll be clad in golden armor and travel the world!
ついには 天下の大将軍となる！
Until we finally become the greatest generals under the heavens!
Great generals?!
大将軍！
And our names will go down in history?!
そして 歴史に名を残すのか！
（漂）そのとおりだ 信
Exactly, Xin.
今は 下僕の身の俺たちだけど
２人の名を将来 歴史に刻むんだ！
We may be servants right now,
but in the future, our names will be carved into history!
（信）ハハハッ… 一体
どれだけ勝ち続ければいいんだよ？
Man, just how many wins in a row are we gonna need for that?
That's simple!
（漂）簡単さ
俺たちは無敵だ　誰にも負けない！
We'll be invincible!
We won't lost to anyone!
That's right...
（信）そうだ
俺の剣は…
My sword...
Our swords...!
俺たちの剣は…
天下に轟(とどろ)く剣だ！
will reach everywhere under the heavens!
誰にも… 誰にも負けねえ！
We won't... lose to anyone!
まだやるか？
（村人たち）ヒイッ！
Still wanna go?
ケッ… バカ野郎が
Idiots.
（信）着いた…
I made it.
The house... where the rivers meet.
川の合流地…
…ということは
So does that mean...
this is it?
これか？
It's just a little shack sunk into the ground.
ただの掘っ立て小屋だ…
ただの掘っ立て小屋だぞ 漂
It's just a shack, Piao!
何なんだよ？ これ
What the hell is this?
俺は お前の敵討ちもせずに―
Without getting revenge for you...
ワケも分からず
こんな所にまで来ちまったぞ
and without knowing what was going on...
I came to this place!
教えろよ 漂
Tell me... Piao.
What did you die for?
お前 なんで死んじまったんだよ？
なんで俺をここに導いた？
こんなボロ小屋に
Why did you lead me...
to this broken down shack?
What on earth is in here?
一体 何があるっていうんだ？
No way...
バカな…
That can't be...
そんなバカな…
ひょ… 漂？
P-Piao...?
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
～♪
Preview
（信）よくも漂を殺しやがったな！
How dare you kill Piao!
あいつは もう…
もう生き返らないんだぞ！
That guy's not... not leaving here alive!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
命を燃やす何かを定めたとき
人の前に道はできる
When something makes a person's spirit burn,
Fated Meeting
a path can form in front of them.
End
Fated Meeting
Next time,
次回 “運命の出会い”
Fated Meeting.